A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, National Affairs Division, Program Staff Files FA576
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Sanford M. Jaffe, 1974-1978; V
  - Heaps, David -- Memoranda and Correspondence Re: London School of Economics Conference on Human Rights Guarantees in British Bill of Rights, Jan-Apr 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Heaps, David -- Memoranda Re: International Human Rights Law and Abuses, Ford Foundation Support for International Organizations, etc., Jul 1974-Dec 1976 (Box 9, Folder 6)
- Eamon Kelly, 1966-1970; VI
  Dr. Kelly's files hold his chronological correspondence files for 1969-1970 and also include Board of Directors meeting minutes, correspondence, memoranda, reports and additional background information on the North Carolina Fund.
  - Chronological Correspondence -- Meeting Notes, Approved Grant Proposal Reviews, 1969 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Chronological Correspondence -- Meeting Notes, Grant Proposal Reviews, etc., 1970 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - North Carolina Fund -- Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, Agenda, etc., 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - North Carolina Fund -- Ford-NCF Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Manpower Development Corporation, Other Grants, 1966-1967 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - North Carolina Fund -- Response to North Carolina Attorney General and News Clippings Re: Political Activism Controversy, Aug-Sep 1967 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - North Carolina Fund -- Review Report, Jan 1967 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- William Pincus, 1955-1967; VII
  William Pincus's files primarily date from the early days of the Foundation's Public Affairs Division. His files contain memoranda on budgeting and grant evaluation. They also hold a selection of Mr. Pincus' writings, particularly on the subject of legal education.
  - American Bar Association -- Correspondence Re: Potential Grant Funding, 1957-1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 1967-1969 -- Budget, Discussion Papers on Youth Offenders, Local Government, Law Program, 1965-1966 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Bundy, McGeorge -- Comments on Draft of President's Review, Jan 24, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Conference on the Civil Service -- Minutes, Correspondence, May 6-7, 1966 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Re: Grants, Proposals, Reviews, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Docket Items -- Memoranda Re: Grant Request Process, 1961-1967 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Educational Television -- Correspondence and Memoranda Re: Support for Presidential Candidate TV Appearances, 1959-1965 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Ernst, Morris -- Suggestions Re: Foundation Support for Law-Related Grants, 1955-1962 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Foundation Procedures -- Grant Modification, Grant Letters, Grant Processing, Inter-Office Memoranda, Rejection Letters, Legal Aspects, Style Guide, etc., 1957-1967 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Foundations -- News Clippings about the Ford Foundation and Congressman Wright Patman's Call for Tax Reform, 1962-1963 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Glickenhaus, Seth M. -- Correspondence Re: Civil Rights Research Council, 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Government and Law Program -- Statement of Purpose, Grant Recommendations, 1967 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Harrington, James -- Research Project on Background of Persons in Public Service, 1960-1963 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Legal Aid in the United States of America and England", Jul 1964 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Memoranda (General) -- Summary of Ford Foundation Law Programs Meeting, Notes on Meetings with Potential Grantees, 1957-1962 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Memoranda (General) -- Re: Staff Titles, Grant Payments, Law Meeting Notes, etc., 1965-1966 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - News Clippings -- Re: Ford Foundation on Education, Law, Tax Exemption, 1959-1966 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Personnel for International Deployment -- Memoranda, 1962 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Public Affairs Docket Items, 1957-1965 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Public Affairs Memoranda -- Notes and Memoranda from Public Affairs Staff Re: Conference, Budget, Internal Policy, etc. (1 of 2), 1959-1963 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Public Affairs Memoranda -- Re: Public Affairs Staff Meeting, Appointments, Internal Policy, etc. (2 of 2), 1964 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Report on Vocational Education as a Field for Foundation Activity, Sep 4, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - State Reapportionment -- Correspondence and Background Re: Congressional Redistricting, 1962-1963 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Travel and Study Awards -- Greenleaf, Robert K. -- Proposal, Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Travel and Study Awards -- Grundstein, Dr. Nathan D. -- Correspondence Re: Potential Grant, 1963-1965 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - University of Pittsburgh -- Correspondence Re: Graduate School of Public and International Affairs, 1958-1960 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Writings -- Miscellaneous Memoranda, Background Papers, Speeches, 1960-1965 (Box 12, Folder 6)